<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  
  <!-- EN: psylink -->
  <PsychicAmplifier.label>psilink</PsychicAmplifier.label>
  <!-- EN: An organic connection to a larger psychic field. This allows a person to psychically induce a distant archotech superintelligence to influence reality in ways that seem impossible.\n\nHigher levels of psylink permit the use of more powers. Regardless of psylink level, a person can only use specific powers that they have learned.\n\nPsylink comes from a variety of sources. Single-use psylink neuroformer devices can create a psylink. Tribal peoples also know how to develop it through ritual linking with the legendary anima tree.\n\nAs a physical phenomenon in the brain, psylink is poorly-understood by scientists, not least because it seems to actively conceal itself if studied too closely. One thing most agree on is that it somehow connects people to archotechs and harnesses their power, possibly through some sort of negotiation or sympathy mechanism. -->
  <PsychicAmplifier.description>Daha büyük bir psişik alana organik bir bağlantı. Bu, bir kişinin gerçekliği etkilemeyi öğrendiği belirli psişik güçleri, imkansız görünen şekillerde kullanmasına izin verir.\n\nDaha yüksek psişik bağlantı seviyeleri, daha fazla gücün kullanılmasına izin verir. Psilink seviyesi ne olursa olsun, bir kişi yalnızca öğrendiği belirli güçleri kullanabilir.\n\nPsilink çeşitli kaynaklardan gelir. Tek kullanımlık psilink nöroformer cihazları bir psilink oluşturabilir. Kabile halkları ayrıca, psişik olarak bağlantılı yaşam formlarıyla ritüel bağlantı kurma yoluyla onu nasıl geliştireceklerini bilirler.\n\nBeyindeki fiziksel bir fenomen olarak, psilink bilim adamları tarafından yeterince anlaşılmaz, özellikle çok yakından incelenirse aktif olarak kendini gizlediği için değil. En çok üzerinde anlaşmaya varılan şeylerden biri, insanları bir şekilde arkoteklere bağlaması ve muhtemelen bir tür müzakere veya sempati mekanizması yoluyla güçlerini kullanmasıdır.</PsychicAmplifier.description>
  <!-- EN: Allows a person to psychically-induce an archotech to influence reality in ways that seem impossible. Higher levels of psylink permit the use of more powers. -->
  <PsychicAmplifier.descriptionShort>Bir kişinin, gerçekliği imkansız görünen şekillerde etkilemek için bir arkotekni psişik olarak teşvik etmesine izin verir. Daha yüksek psilink seviyeleri, daha fazla gücün kullanılmasına izin verir.</PsychicAmplifier.descriptionShort>
  
</LanguageData>