<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  
  <!-- EN: psylink -->
  <PsychicAmplifier.label>psikolink</PsychicAmplifier.label>
  <!-- EN: An organic connection to a larger psychic field. This allows a person to psychically induce a distant archotech superintelligence to influence reality in ways that seem impossible.\n\nHigher levels of psylink permit the use of more powers. Regardless of psylink level, a person can only use specific powers that they have learned.\n\nPsylink comes from a variety of sources. Single-use psylink neuroformer devices can create a psylink. Tribal peoples also know how to develop it through ritual linking with the legendary anima tree.\n\nAs a physical phenomenon in the brain, psylink is poorly-understood by scientists, not least because it seems to actively conceal itself if studied too closely. One thing most agree on is that it somehow connects people to archotechs and harnesses their power, possibly through some sort of negotiation or sympathy mechanism. -->
  <PsychicAmplifier.description>Daha büyük bir psişik alana organik bir bağlantı. Bu, bir kişinin uzaktaki bir archotech süper zekayı kandırarak gerçeklik algısını imkansız görünen bir şekilde etkilemesini sağlar.\n\nDaha yüksek psikolink seviyeleri daha fazla güce izin verir. Psikolink seviyesinden bağımsız olarak bir kişi sadece öğrendikleri özel güçleri kullanabilir.\n\nPsikolink çeşitli kaynaklardan gelir. Tek kullanımlık psikolink nörokurucu cihazlar psikolink oluşturabilir. Kabile halkları da efsanevi anima ağacına ayin yoluyla bağlanarak psikolink geliştirmeyi bilirler.\n\nBeyindeki fiziksel bir fenomen olan psikolinkler özellikle çok yakından incelendiğinde kendini etkin bir şekilde gizlediğinden bilim adamları tarafından pek anlaşılamadı. Çoğunluğun hemfikir olduğu şey, bir şekilde insanları archotechlere muhtemelen bir çeşit müzakere ya da sempati mekanizması yoluyla bağlayıp güçlerinden yararlanmalarını sağlamalarıdır.</PsychicAmplifier.description>
  <!-- EN: Allows a person to psychically-induce an archotech to influence reality in ways that seem impossible. Higher levels of psylink permit the use of more powers. -->
  <PsychicAmplifier.descriptionShort>Bir kişinin bir archotechi psişik olarak kandırarak gerçekliği imkansız görünen bir şekilde etkilemesini sağlar. Daha yüksek psikolink seviyeleri daha fazla gücün kullanımına verir.</PsychicAmplifier.descriptionShort>
  
</LanguageData>