<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  
  <!-- EN: baseliner -->
  <Baseliner.label>temel</Baseliner.label>
  <!-- EN: A naturally-evolved human with no major significant genetic modifications. -->
  <Baseliner.description>Önemli bir genetik modifikasyonu olmayan, doğal olarak evrimleşmiş bir insan.</Baseliner.description>
  
  <!-- EN: dirtmole -->
  <Dirtmole.label>köstebek</Dirtmole.label>
  <!-- EN: With gray skin adapted to artificial light, they thrive in cramped and dark spaces where combat and travel happen over short distances. They are extremely capable at digging or mining tasks. In the open, however, they suffer from a sensitivity to light, slow speed and poor eyesight at distance.\n\nAfter the first tunnel colonies failed due to the stress of confinement, colonization agencies began genetically altering colonists to live without open space or sunlight. This xenotype is known colloquially as the dirtmoles. Today, dirtmoles have expanded out of their original tunnel homes and rule many confined spaces in the anthrosphere. They can be found in deep mines, cramped low-tech spacecraft, and teeming by the billions in the dark underlayers of countless urbworlds. -->
  <Dirtmole.description>Yapay ışığa adapte olmuş gri tenleriyle, çatışmaların ve seyahatlerin kısa mesafelerde gerçekleştiği sıkışık, karanlık alanlarda başarılıdırlar. Kazı veya maden işlerinde son derece yeteneklidirler. Lakin açık alanda, ışığa karşı duyarlılık, yavaş hareket ve zayıf uzak mesafe görüşü gibi dezavantajlar yaşarlar.\n\nİlk tünel kolonileri, kapalı alanda yaşamanın getirdiği stres nedeniyle başarısız olduktan sonra, kolonizasyon ajansları, açık alan ya da güneş ışığı olmaksızın yaşayabilmeleri için kolonistleri genetik olarak değiştirmeye başladı. Bu zenotip, halk arasında "köstebekler" olarak bilinir. Bugün, köstebekler kendilerine özgü tünel evlerinden çıkarak antrokozferdeki birçok kapalı alanı yönetmekte; derin madenlerde, sıkışık düşük teknolojili uzay gemilerinde ve sayısız şehirdünyanın karanlık alt katmanlarında milyarlarca adet bulunabilmektedir.</Dirtmole.description>
  <!-- EN: With gray skin adapted to artificial light, dirtmoles thrive in cramped and dark spaces where combat and travel happen over short distances. They are naturals at digging and navigating complex tunnel structures. In the open, they suffer from a sensitivity to light, slow speed and poor eyesight at distance. -->
  <Dirtmole.descriptionShort>Yapay ışığa uyum sağlamış gri tenli köstebekler, çatışmaların ve seyahatlerin kısa mesafelerde gerçekleştiği sıkışık, karanlık alanlarda başarılıdırlar. Kazma ve karmaşık tünel yapılarını dolaşma konusunda doğuştan yeteneklidirler. Lakin açık alanda, ışığa karşı duyarlılık, yavaş hareket ve zayıf uzak mesafe görüşü gibi dezavantajlarla karşılaşırlar.</Dirtmole.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: genie -->
  <Genie.label>cin</Genie.label>
  <!-- EN: Designed to be engineers, genies' delicate bones and natural aptitude with machines allow them to manipulate devices with remarkable precision. They are emotionally cold and can follow orders where others might panic. However, they are fragile, and their amplified nerve impulses make them easy to debilitate with relatively little pain. With so much of their brains dedicated to analyzing machines, they lack the neural hardware to analyze emotions, so they sometimes come off as socially inept. Their dead calm makes it even harder for them to relate to what they see as madly-hotheaded baseliner humans.\n\nGenies were engineered thousands of years ago by a long-disbanded space navy to hold engineering positions on large starships. Today, genies still serve as engineers in great cities and fleets, but many can also be found working as lawyers, pilots, and musicians. -->
  <Genie.description>Mühendis olarak tasarlanan cinlerin narin kemikleri ve makinelere olan doğal yatkınlıkları, cihazları olağanüstü bir hassasiyetle kontrol etmelerini sağlar. Duygusal olarak soğuk olup, diğerlerinin panikleyebileceği durumlarda bile emirleri yerine getirebilirler. Lakin, kırılgandırlar; yükseltilmiş sinir impulsları, onları nispeten az acı ile kolayca etkisiz hâle getirebilir. Zihinlerinin büyük bir kısmını makineleri analiz etmeye ayırdıklarından, duyguları çözümleyecek nöral altyapıya sahip değiller. Bu yüzden bazen sosyal olarak beceriksiz görünürler. Soğukkanlılıkları, kendileri için çılgınca öfkeli ve sıradan olan insanlarla empati kurmalarını daha da güçleştirir.\n\nBinlerce yıl önce dağıtılmış bir uzay donanması tarafından büyük yıldız gemilerinde mühendislik pozisyonlarını doldurmak üzere üretilen cinler, bugün hâlâ büyük şehirler ve filolarda mühendis olarak görev yapıyor. Ancak pek çoğu, avukat, pilot ve müzisyen olarak da çalışıyor.</Genie.description>
  <!-- EN: Designed to be engineers, genies have natural aptitude with machines, and are emotionally cold and calm. They are also fragile and vulnerable to pain. Focused on machines, they often come off as socially inept. -->
  <Genie.descriptionShort>Mühendis olarak tasarlanan cinler, makinelere doğal bir yatkınlığa sahip olup duygusal olarak soğuk ve sakindirler. Ayrıca, kırılgandırlar ve acıya karşı hassastırlar. Makinelere odaklandıkları için, genellikle sosyal açıdan beceriksiz görünürler.</Genie.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: highmate -->
  <Highmate.label>yüksek eş</Highmate.label>
  <!-- EN: Designed companions and concubines with a unique ability to psychically bond with a mate, highmates are empathic, beautiful, cheerful, and talented in social matters. They are also inept at manual tasks, physically weak, and mentally incapable of violence.\n\nOn a few wealthy worlds, highmate xenogerms are commercially available and some people become highmates as a sort of career. However, many societies find them abhorrent, either because they distract people from forming natural families, or because they are humans shaped to serve the pleasures of another. On such worlds they are either reserved as playthings of the powerful, or banned entirely. This particular line of highmate fits the fashions of classical Novaroma, but many other variants exist. -->
  <Highmate.description>Özel olarak tasarlanmış dostlar ve cariyeler olan yüksek eşler, eşleriyle psişik bağ kurma konusunda benzersiz bir yeteneğe sahiptir. Empatik, güzel, neşeli ve sosyal konularda yetenekli olan yüksek eşler, aynı zamanda el işlerinde beceriksiz, fiziksel olarak zayıf ve zihinsel olarak şiddete elverişli değillerdir.\n\nBirkaç zengin gezegende yüksek eş zenogermleri ticari olarak satışa sunulmaktadır ve bazı kişiler bunu bir kariyer seçeneği olarak benimsemektedir. Lakin, birçok toplum ya insanların doğal aileler kurmalarını engelledikleri gerekçesiyle ya da başkalarının zevklerine hizmet etmek üzere şekillendirilmiş insan varlıkları oldukları için yüksek eşleri iğrenç bulmaktadır. Bu tür gezegenlerde yüksek eşler ya güçlülerin eğlencesi olarak ayrılmakta ya da tamamen yasaklanmaktadır. Bu yüksek eş soyu, klasik Novaroma modasına uygundur ancak pek çok farklı çeşidi de bulunmaktadır.</Highmate.description>
  <!-- EN: Designed companions and concubines with a unique ability to psychically bond with a mate, highmates are empathic, beautiful, cheerful, and talented in social matters. They are also inept at manual tasks, physically weak, and mentally incapable of violence. -->
  <Highmate.descriptionShort>Özel olarak tasarlanmış dostlar ve cariyeler olan yüksek eşler, eşleriyle psişik bağ kurma konusunda benzersiz bir yeteneğe sahiptir. Empatik, güzel, neşeli ve sosyal konularda yeteneklidirler. Lakin, el işlerinde beceriksiz, fiziksel olarak zayıf ve zihinsel olarak şiddet uygulayamazlar.</Highmate.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: hussar -->
  <Hussar.label>hussar</Hussar.label>
  <!-- EN: Hussars are engineered soldiers. They fight aggressively and with precision, heal fast, thrive in extreme temperatures, and freely ingest military drugs. They have a genetic dependence on go-juice, which also makes them less likely to rebel against their commanders.\n\nWhile hussars' emotions make them dangerous in combat, they can't relate to baseliner humans. They are famous for their blood-red eyes and "hussar stare", a dead expression that unsettles many people. Their lack of expression and burning aggressive nature has led to many violent misunderstandings.\n\nIn most societies where they live, hussars are kept separated from the rest of the population. Hussars are single-purpose tools - and they generally aren't bothered by the fact. -->
  <Hussar.description>Hussarlar, tasarlanmış askerlerdir. Saldırgan ve hassas bir şekilde dövüşür, hızlı iyileşir, aşırı sıcaklık koşullarında başarılı olurlar ve askeri uyuşturucuları serbestçe tüketirler. Mazota genetik bir bağımlılıkları vardır. Bu durum, komutanlarına karşı isyan etmelerini de zorlaştırır.\n\nHussarların duyguları, çatışmalarda onları tehlikeli kılarken temel insanlarla empati kurmalarını engeller. Kan kırmızısı gözleri ve "hussar bakışı" ile ünlüdürler. Bu bakış, ifadesizliğiyle pek çok kişiyi tedirgin eder. İfade eksiklikleri ve aşırı saldırgan doğaları, birçok şiddetli yanlış anlaşılmaya yol açmıştır.\n\nYaşadıkları çoğu toplumda, hussarlar nüfusun geri kalanından ayrı tutulur. Hussarlar, tek amaçlı araçlardır ve genellikle bu durum onları rahatsız etmez.</Hussar.description>
  <!-- EN: Hussars are engineered soldiers. They fight aggressively and with precision, heal fast, thrive in extreme temperatures, and freely ingest military drugs. They have a genetic dependence on go-juice. -->
  <Hussar.descriptionShort>Hussarlar, tasarlanmış askerlerdir. Saldırgan ve hassas biçimde dövüşür, hızlı iyileşir, aşırı sıcaklık koşullarında başarılı olurlar ve askeri uyuşturucuları serbestçe tüketirler. Mazota genetik bir bağımlılıkları vardır.</Hussar.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: impid -->
  <Impid.label>İmpid</Impid.label>
  <!-- EN: Made for desert life, impid cultures live on many rimworlds and dry deathworlds. Impids are extremely fast-moving, easily tolerate high temperatures, and can spew fire from their mouths. Though they are masters on the sand, impids struggle in other environments. They are terrible with farming. They fight well at range, but in close combat their physical weakness becomes apparent.\n\nOutlanders call them dustrunners because of their speed over open terrain and resistance to heat. Some tribes call them devils because of their horns and because they burn their enemies. Impid tribes' combat tactics usually center on rapid-approach incendiary attacks using both handheld fire weapons and their fire spew ability. -->
  <Impid.description>Çöl yaşamına uygun olarak tasarlanmış impidler, birçok kenardünya ve kuru ölüdünyada yaşarlar. İmpidler son derece hızlı hareket eder, yüksek sıcaklıklara kolayca dayanır ve ağızlarından ateş püskürtebilirler. Kumda ustalaşmış olsalar da diğer çevre koşullarında zorlanırlar. Tarımda ise son derece beceriksizdirler; uzaktan dövüşte başarılıyken, yakın muharebede fiziksel zayıflıkları ortaya çıkar.\n\nYabancılar, açık arazideki hızları ve ısıya dayanıklılıkları nedeniyle onlara "toz koşucuları" derler. Bazı kabileler, boynuzları ve düşmanlarını yakmaları yüzünden onları şeytan olarak adlandırır. İmpid kabilelerinin savaş taktikleri ise hem elde taşınabilen ateşli silahları hem de ağızlarından ateş püskürtme yeteneklerini kullanarak hızlı yakınlaşma ve ateşli saldırılara dayanır.</Impid.description>
  <!-- EN: Made for desert life, impids are very fast, can spew fire from their mouths, and easily tolerate high temperatures. They fight well at range, but in close combat they do little damage. They are terrible with farming, and have weak immune systems. -->
  <Impid.descriptionShort>Çöl yaşamına uygun olarak tasarlanmış impidler çok hızlıdır, ağızlarından ateş püskürtebilir ve yüksek sıcaklıklara kolayca dayanırlar. Uzaktan dövüşte başarılı olsalar da yakın dövüşte çok az hasar verebilirler. Tarımda son derece beceriksizdirler ve zayıf bağışıklık sistemlerine sahiptirler.</Impid.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: neanderthal -->
  <Neanderthal.label>neandertal</Neanderthal.label>
  <!-- EN: Neanderthals are stocky, powerfully-built humanoids. Their most salient characteristic is that they are difficult to hurt: They are very resistant to injury, and their strong immune systems protect them from infection. However, without ever having evolved in a complex civilization, they are less adept than baseliner humans at intellectual and social tasks, and their impulsiveness can make them dangerously aggressive.\n\nHomo neanderthalensis was originally an archaic population of hominids that emerged over 200,000 years ago during the Pleistocene epoch. After they were replaced by and merged with humans 30,000 years ago, they were absent for tens of thousands of years until scientists resurrected them from ancient DNA. Neanderthals now survive in sub-societies on some settled planets. On the rimworlds, neanderthal tribes carve out the same existence as their Earth ancestors did so long ago. -->
  <Neanderthal.description>Neandertaller, tıknaz ve sağlam yapılı insansı varlıklardır. En belirgin özellikleri, yaralanmalarının zor olmasıdır. Yaralanmalara karşı son derece dirençlidirler ve güçlü bağışıklık sistemleri enfeksiyonlara karşı koruma sağlar. Lakin, karmaşık medeniyetlerde evrimleşmemiş olmaları sebebiyle, entelektüel ve sosyal görevlerde temel insanlardan daha yetersizdirler. Dürtüsellikleri ise onları tehlikeli derecede saldırgan yapabilir.\n\nHomo neanderthalensis, ilk olarak Pleistosen döneminde, 200.000 yıldan fazla önce ortaya çıkan arkaik bir hominid popülasyonuydu. 30.000 yıl önce insanlar tarafından yerlerinden edilip onlarla birleştikten sonra, on binlerce yıl boyunca ortadan kaybolmuşlardı; ta ki bilim insanları antik DNA'dan yeniden canlandırana kadar. Neandertaller, artık bazı yerleşik gezegenlerde alt toplumlar hâlinde hayatta kalmaktadır. Neandertal kabileleri, atalarının çok uzun zaman önce sahip olduğu yaşam biçimini kenardünyalarda yeniden oluştururlar.</Neanderthal.description>
  <!-- EN: Neanderthals are stocky, powerfully-built humanoids. They are hardy and difficult to injure, and their strong immune systems protect them from infection. However, their minds are less adept at intellectual and social tasks, and their impulsiveness can make them dangerously aggressive. -->
  <Neanderthal.descriptionShort>Neandertaller, tıknaz ve güçlü yapılı insansı varlıklardır. Dayanıklıdırlar ve yaralanmaları zordur; güçlü bağışıklık sistemleri enfeksiyonlara karşı onları korur. Lakin, zihinleri entelektüel ve sosyal görevlerde daha az yetkindir ve dürtüsellikleri onları tehlikeli derecede saldırgan yapabilir.</Neanderthal.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: pigskin -->
  <Pigskin.label>domuzderili</Pigskin.label>
  <!-- EN: Pigskins are human-pig hybrids which are capable of two-legged movement, tool use, and speech, but which also retain many pig-like qualities. They are hardy and can eat almost anything without getting sick, but their trotter-shaped hands leave them at a disadvantage when attempting to precisely manipulate tools and objects. They don't see well at a distance, so pigskin gangs usually focus on close-range weapons. They also have a strong taste for explosives.\n\nPigskins were made for their organs. Uncomfortable with the idea of harvesting organs from baseliner humans, a long-gone government merged human DNA into pigs to make the animals produce more easily-transplantable hearts and lungs. They succeeded, but the resulting creatures became more humanlike than anyone anticipated. -->
  <Pigskin.description>Domuzderililer, iki ayak üzerinde hareket edebilen, alet kullanabilen ve konuşabilen insan-domuz melezleridir; fakat aynı zamanda pek çok domuza özgü özelliği de korurlar. Dayanıklıdırlar ve neredeyse her şeyi yiyebilirler ancak domuz toynağı şeklindeki elleri, aletleri ve nesneleri hassas biçimde kullanma konusunda dezavantaj yaratır. Uzak mesafeyi iyi göremezler, bu yüzden domuzderili çeteleri genellikle yakın mesafeli silahlara yönelir. Ayrıca patlayıcılara karşı büyük bir ilgileri vardır.\n\nDomuzderililer, organları için üretildiler. Temel insanlardan organ hasadı fikrinden rahatsız olan, artık var olmayan bir hükûmet, insan DNA'sını domuzlara entegre ederek hayvanların daha kolay nakledilebilen kalp ve akciğerler üretmesini sağlamıştı. Başarılı oldular ama ortaya çıkan yaratıklar, beklenenden çok daha insansı hâle geldi.</Pigskin.description>
  <!-- EN: Pigskins are human-pig hybrids. They are hardy and can eat almost anything without getting sick, but their trotter-shaped hands are bad at fine manipulation. They don't see well at a distance, so they usually focus on close-range weapons. They have a strong taste for explosives. -->
  <Pigskin.descriptionShort>Domuzderililer, insan-domuz melezleridir. Dayanıklıdırlar ve neredeyse her şeyi hastalanmadan yiyebilirler fakat domuz toynağı şeklindeki elleri ince beceri gerektiren işlemlerde yetersizdir. Uzak mesafeleri iyi göremediklerinden, genellikle yakın mesafeli silahlara yönelirler. Patlayıcılara karşı büyük bir düşkünlükleri vardır.</Pigskin.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: sanguophage -->
  <Sanguophage.label>sanguofaj</Sanguophage.label>
  <!-- EN: Sanguophages are a type of archotech-enhanced xenohuman. Powered by archites, their abilities go far beyond normal genetic enhancements. They are mentally adept and preternaturally beautiful. In combat, they can launch deadly spines and heal injured friends. They don't age or die naturally and never suffer from disease or poison. A sanguophage can make a new sanguophage by reimplanting their own xenogerm into a person.\n\nSanguophages must regularly consume hemogen derived from human blood, and they must periodically deathrest for long periods. They're easily destroyed by fire, and slowed down by UV light.\n\nThe first sanguophage appeared thousands of years ago when the lord-explorer Varan-Dur sought to control a hyperintelligent archotech and found himself transformed by it instead. Every sanguophage is descended from him. Since then, sanguophages have often been hunted because of their destabilizing power and their need for blood. Since they can pass for baseliners, many live in hiding among typical humans.\n\nTheir numbers are unknown. Some think they are legends or rare irrelevancies. Some believe sanguophages secretly direct entire human civilizations. The stories speak of eternal lords ruling billions from slate-black space stations, or directing blood sacrifices at conferences in the underlayers of the deepest urbworlds. -->
  <Sanguophage.description>Sanguofajlar, arkotek destekli zenoinsan türlerinden biridir. Arkitlerden güç alırlar, yetenekleri sıradan genetik geliştirmelerin çok ötesine geçer. Zihinsel olarak yetkin ve doğaüstü güzelliktedirler. Savaşta ölümcül dikenler fırlatabilir, yaralı arkadaşlarını iyileştirebilirler. Doğal olarak yaşlanmaz veya ölmezler; hastalık ya da zehirlenmeye yakalanmazlar. Bir sanguofaj, kendi zenogermini bir kişiye enjekte ederek onu sanguofaj yapabilir.\n\nSanguofajlar, düzenli olarak insan kanından elde edilen hemojen tüketmeli ve belirli aralıklarla uzun süreli ölüm uykusuna yatmalıdır. Ateş onları kolayca yok eder ve UV ışığı onları yavaşlatır.\n\nİlk sanguofaj, binlerce yıl önce lord-kâşif Varan-Dur'un hiperzeki bir arkoteki kontrol altına almaya çalıştığı sırada, bunun etkisiyle dönüşüme uğraması sonucu ortaya çıktı. Her sanguofaj ondan türemiştir. O zamandan beri, sanguofajlar dengesizlik yaratan güçleri ve kan ihtiyaçları nedeniyle sıkça avlanmaktadırlar. Temel insanlar gibi görünebildikleri için pek çoğu tipik insanlar arasında saklanarak yaşar.\n\nSayıları bilinmemektedir. Bazıları onların efsane ya da nadir önemsiz varlıklar olduğuna inanırken, bazıları ise sanguofajların tüm insan medeniyetlerini gizlice yönettiğine inanır. Hikâyeler, füme-siyah uzay istasyonlarından milyarlarca kişiye hükmeden ebedi lordları ya da en derin şehirdünyaların alt katmanlarındaki konferanslarda kan kurbanlarını yöneten varlıkları anlatır.</Sanguophage.description>
  <!-- EN: Sanguophages are ageless, deathless super-humans powered by archotech-created archites in the bloodstream. They are beautiful and extremely intelligent. They can heal any injury, and never suffer from disease or poison. In combat, they can launch deadly spines and heal injured friends. The price is that sanguophages must consume hemogen derived from human blood to survive, and they must periodically deathrest for long periods. They're easily destroyed by fire, and slowed down by UV light. -->
  <Sanguophage.descriptionShort>Sanguofajlar, arkotek tarafından oluşturulan arkitlerden güç alan, yaşlanmayan, ölümsüz süper insanlardır. Güzel ve son derece zekidirler. Herhangi bir yaralanmayı iyileştirebilirler ve asla hastalık ya da zehirlenmeye yakalanmazlar. Savaş sırasında, ölümcül dikenler fırlatabilir ve yaralı dostlarını iyileştirebilirler. Bedeli ise, hayatta kalabilmek için insan kanından elde edilen hemojen tüketmeleri ve belirli aralıklarla uzun süreli ölüm uykusuna yatmalarıdır. Ateşe karşı kolayca yok olurlar ve UV ışığı onları yavaşlatır.</Sanguophage.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: waster -->
  <Waster.label>atıkçı</Waster.label>
  <!-- EN: Wasters are aggressive, immune to toxic pollution, almost impervious to disease, and can ingest as much psychite and wake-up drugs as they wish with no ill effects. Their toxin-adapted metabolism means they must consume some form of psychite - usually flake or yayo.\n\nOriginally engineered to prevent resettlement of post-apocalyptic deathworlds, wasters are living area-denial weapons. Waster pirates armed with toxic weapons are the bane of many frontier peoples, both on the rimworlds and in the depths of the urbworld hyperstructures. -->
  <Waster.description>Atıkçılar agresiftir, toksik kirliliğe karşı bağışıklıdır, hastalıklardan neredeyse etkilenmezler ve psikit ile gece kuşu ilaçlarını hiçbir yan etki olmaksızın istedikleri kadar tüketebilirler. Toksinlere adapte metabolizmaları, genellikle kristal ya da yayo şeklinde olan bir psikit formu tüketmelerini gerektirir.\n\nPost-apokaliptik ölüdünyaların yeniden yerleşimini önlemek amacıyla tasarlanmış olan atıkçılar, yaşayan alan reddi silahlarıdır. Toksik silahlarla donatılmış atıkçı korsanları, hem kenardünyalarda hem de şehirdünya hiper yapılarının derinliklerinde birçok sınır topluluğuna bela olurlar.</Waster.description>
  <!-- EN: Wasters are aggressive, immune to toxic pollution, almost impervious to disease, and can ingest as much psychite and wake-up drugs as they wish with no ill effects. Their toxin-adapted metabolism means they must consume some form of psychite - usually flake or yayo. -->
  <Waster.descriptionShort>Atıkçılar agresiftir, toksik kirliliğe karşı bağışıklıdır, hastalıklardan neredeyse etkilenmezler ve psikit ile gece kuşu ilaçlarını hiçbir yan etki olmaksızın istedikleri kadar tüketebilirler. Toksinlere adapte metabolizmaları, genellikle kristal ya da yayo şeklinde bir psikit formu tüketmelerini gerektirir.</Waster.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: yttakin -->
  <Yttakin.label>yttakin</Yttakin.label>
  <!-- EN: Yttakin descend from colonists engineered to thrive on ultra-cold planets. Their great size and fur make them hardy in frozen environments. Yttakin share a psychic connection with the wildlife and can summon animals to their side during battles. They are not fast or energetic or precise, but can keep going when others would have collapsed long before.\n\nSince they migrated off their icy birthworld of Yttak, Yttakin settlements live on many planets. Their fur, roaring voices, and aversion to urban living sometimes leads naive outsiders to believe they are simple-minded animals. Quick-minded Yttakin are happy to make good use of such wrong beliefs, whether at the negotiating table or on the battlefield. -->
  <Yttakin.description>Yttakin, ultra soğuk gezegenlerde hayatta kalmaları için üretilen kolonistlerin soyundan gelir. Büyük boyutları ve kürkleri, donmuş çevrelere dayanıklı olmalarını sağlar. Yttakin, yaban hayatıyla psişik bir bağ paylaşır ve savaş sırasında yanlarına hayvanları çağırabilir. Hızlı, enerjik ya da hassas değillerdir; diğerleri çoktan çökmüşken onlar yoluna devam edebilirler.\n\nHayata geldikleri buzlu Yttak gezegeninden göç ettikten sonra birçok gezegende yerleşimler kurmuşlardır. Kürkleri, gürleyen sesleri ve kentsel yaşamdan kaçınmaları, bazen yabancıların onları basit zihinli hayvanlar olarak görmesine neden olur. Zeki Yttakin, ister pazarlık masasının başında ister savaş alanında olsun, bu yanlış inançlardan lehlerine faydalanmaktan mutluluk duyarlar.</Yttakin.description>
  <!-- EN: Yttakin descend from colonists engineered to thrive on ultra-cold planets. Their great size and fur make them hardy in frozen environments, and they have a unique ability to communicate vocally and psychically with animals. They are not fast or energetic or precise, but can keep going when others would have collapsed long before. -->
  <Yttakin.descriptionShort>Yttakin, ultra soğuk gezegenlerde hayatta kalmaları için üretilen kolonistlerin soyundan gelir. Büyük boyutları ve kürkleri, onları donmuş çevrelere dayanıklı kılar. Ayrıca, hayvanlarla hem sesli hem de psişik olarak iletişim kurabilme konusunda benzersiz bir yeteneğe sahiptirler. Hızlı, enerjik ya da hassas değillerdir; diğerleri çoktan çökmüşken onlar yoluna devam edebilirler.</Yttakin.descriptionShort>
  
</LanguageData>